<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Vincent F.</title>
		<description>Projects list</description>
		<link>http://VincentFalc.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://VincentFalc.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Shape Modeling Forces simulation</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was linked to a lecture about Shape Modeling. This project presents a method to obtain the stable position of a mesh constrained under forces. The simulation is mainly based on Springs.
&lt;br /&gt;
The main idea is to compare the mesh with a Spring’s network. Then, the problem is to minimize the global stress (which’s the sum of the individual Spring stress) of the mesh, by an optimization method. Here again we are talking about reducing the energy of the mesh.
&lt;br /&gt;
We have choices on the Spring modelisation and the optimization method. We will go through first order optimization (Gradient descent) and second order optimization (Newton’s method).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi5/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi5/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Shape Modeling Deformation and editing</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was linked to a lecture about Shape Modeling. This project presents a method to deform meshs, based on high frequency details conservation and low frequency forms deformation, to keep a good integrity of the mesh during the edition.
&lt;br /&gt;
The editing method is real-time for small to medium meshes on a medium-class laptop computer.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi4/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi4/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Shape Modeling Texture mapping</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was linked to a lecture about Shape Modeling. This project presents different parametization methods : we map 3D points in a 2D space, to apply modification (Especially when it’s simpler in 2D, like texture mapping, etc.), to get back to 3D space.
&lt;br /&gt;
Mapping 3D meshs to 2D (“flat”) space involved stretching, shrinking, … and so globally, deformations. When we proceed to such process, we try to reduce this deformation. Assuming we try to reduce deformation, the parametization will depend on the way we compute deformation.
&lt;br /&gt;
We will see 4 methods :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spring energy (uniform Laplacian)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dirichlet/harmonic energy (cotangent Laplacian)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Least Squares Conformal Maps (LSCM)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As-Rigid-As-Possible (ARAP)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi3/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi3/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Shape Modeling Surface reconstruction</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was linked to a lecture about Shape Modeling. This project presents a way to compute the surface of a point cloud, with normals.
Note that without normals, we would need preprocess the point cloud by creating local plan, to produce normals ; and by using a spanning tree, to propagate one global direction (ext/int) to all normals.
&lt;br /&gt;
The goal to find a function, which has a 0-value on the surface. It has a positive value outside the mesh, a negative value inside the mesh.
&lt;br /&gt;
This problem is similar to an interpolation problem, and therefore we need to create a constraint system to solve (the value the function should have at each known point).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Shape Modeling IGL Library</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was linked to a lecture about Shape Modeling. This project presents primitives to manipulate data with the IGL and Eigen libraries.
These librairies are not well documented and therefore understand the implementation of some trivial operations might be time-consuming. This project try to show some basics with the library. It leads to a very basic blender-like real-time mesh editor.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://VincentFalc.github.io/ShapeModeling-Assi1/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
