<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Vincent F.</title>
		<description>Projects list</description>
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Shape Modeling Surface reconstruction</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was linked to a lecture about Shape Modeling. This project presents a way to compute the surface of a point cloud, with normals.
Note that without normals, we would need preprocess the point cloud by creating local plan, to produce normals ; and by using a spanning tree, to propagate one global direction (ext/int) to all normals.
&lt;br /&gt;
The goal to find a function, which has a 0-value on the surface. It has a positive value outside the mesh, a negative value inside the mesh.
&lt;br /&gt;
This problem is similar to an interpolation problem, and therefore we need to create a constraint system to solve (the value the function should have at each known point).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/ShapeModeling-Assi2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/ShapeModeling-Assi2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Shape Modeling IGL Library</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was linked to a lecture about Shape Modeling. This project presents primitives to manipulate data with the IGL and Eigen libraries.
These librairies are not well documented and therefore understand the implementation of some trivial operations might be time-consuming. This project try to show some basics with the library. It leads to a very basic blender-like real-time mesh editor.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/ShapeModeling-Assi1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/ShapeModeling-Assi1/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
